YASHVARDHAN C. N.

GitHub | LinkedIn +91 7899900506 | yashvardhancn44@gmail.com



SUMMARY:

A disciplined professional, experienced in projects related to **web**, **big data**, **machine learning** and **cloud technologies**. Former software engineer at **CISCO Systems** and a freelance developer. Having the ability to deliver high-quality software solutions on time and to lead, manage and work with cross-cultural teams.

SKILLS:

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL.
- Web: React.js, Next.js, Express.js, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Jasmine, Jest.
- Data: Confluent Kafka, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- Cloud and Artificial Intelligence: AWS Services, OpenCV, Keras, Scikit-learn.
- Git, BitBucket, OOPS, Data Structures, System Design, Postman.
- Soft Skills: Leader, Agile Learner, Persistent, Adaptive, Humble, Collaborative, Communicative, Multi-lingual.

EXPERIENCE:

CISCO Systems: Software Engineer

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

- Part of the financial reporting team of CISCO as a software developer, developing big data and web applications.
- Developed a **Kafka consumer for data retrieval** using Python, Kafka, and PostgreSQL, optimizing the transfer of **1** million data records in **130** seconds thereby **saving time and cost** for the team.
- Developed a dashboard web application for POC using ReactJS to upgrade from Angular to React.

Freelance Developer

Dec 2021 – Aug 2024

- 4U Academy: Designed and created a web application for an Ed-tech startup using ReactJS.
- **Personal Freelance:** Developed a **AI integrated web application** using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Keras-Tensorflow, and Python-Flask to predict **10** tomato leaf diseases with a prediction accuracy of **87**%.
- · Break: Family Business

Dec 2021 – Aug 2024

PROJECTS:

- E-commerce website
 - Full stack website using MERN, with features such as creating products, user authentication, products searching, checkout process, private routes for admin, user profile management, pagination,
 - Tech: React.js, Redux-toolkit, MongoDB, Express.js, JSON Web Token and Bootstrap.
- · Food Delivery Website
 - Full stack website with features such as searching restaurant, adding to cart, checkout and stripe payment gateway, user authentication using AuthO, create and manage restaurant, order status tracking etc.
 - Tech: React.js, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Auth0, Stripe, TypeScript, Shadcn, Tailwind.
- Hand gesture recognition system.
 - A 2D vision-based system, having the ability to classify images in complex varying lighting conditions and background. It is trained on a self created dataset with 24,000 image and has 93% classification accuracy.
 - Tech: Python, OpenCV, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Scikit-Image and SVM classifier.
- Geolocation system: A real time geo-location tracking system using GPS module, Arduino, Firebase.
- Authentication Website: User authentication, add and edit profile functionality using MERN and JWT.
- Amazon website Clone: E-com website frontend using HTML, CSS, Vanilla JS and Jasmine for testing.
- YouTube Clone: A static frontend website using HTML, CSS only.

EDUCATION

• Siddaganga Institute of Technology, B.E. in Electronics & Communication - 8.62 CGPA

LEADERSHIP AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Published 3 research papers in IEEE and Springer (LINKS).
- Vice Chairperson at IEEE SIT Student Branch: Strategically led a cross cultural team of 117 people in coordinating national-level events during Covid-19, engaging 1000+ participants. Managed 10+ workshops, hackathons, competitions. Led the design, marketing and sponsorship team for 3 straight years.
- **Basketball player:** Secured **1**st **place** representing college in Central Zonal VTU Tournament 2018-2019 and represented Chikmagaluru 2 times in **State Level** Basketball Competitions.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- AWS cloud practitioner essentials Coursera.
- CCNA Certification CISCO.
- Python Certification OpenEDG Python Institute.